Ethan Wager

Salem, NH 03079

Phone: (774) 218 5559 | Email: ethanbwager@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanwager/ | GitHub: https://github.com/Ewager1
Portfolio: https://ewager1.github.io/react-portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in business management and customer relations. Effective at complex problem solving. Known among co-workers for quickly learning new technologies, and for adding a high degree of polish to the client view.

Technical Skills

Front end: React, JavaScript, CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap, AOS-Animations, Bootstrap, jQuery, Mobile-First Design, Progressive Web Apps.

Back end: MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, Sequelize, NodeJS, Express, Rest API's, Routing, Auth0.

Projects

Dev Fit https://github.com/DustinErwin/Devfit | https://dev-fit-gym-app.herokuapp.com/

- Faster, user-friendly gym management software for members, employees, and managers. Handles complex schedule logic quickly and seamlessly.
- Lead UX, UI, and mobile first implementation, form verification, and schedule functionality. Worked closely with backend team to build efficient, lightweight APIs.
- React, React-Bootstrap, Express, Mongoose, Day-Js, Auth0, JS, CSS.

Directory https://github.com/Ewager1/employee-directory | https://u0rol.csb.app/

- Employee Directory app that inputs employee data and outputs a clean, organized view.
- Sole Developer.
- React, React-Bootstrap, React-Tables, Axios, Random-user API, JS, CSS.

Weather App https://github.com/Ewager1/Weather-App | https://ewager1.github.io/Weather-App/

- Displays 5 day forecast for Boston area or any US city.
- Sole Developer.
- Js, CSS, HTML5, Open-Weather-App API

Experience

Elite Freestyle Karate Manager

2013 - 2020

Bedford, Ma

Oversaw sales, retention, and upgrades, and day-to-day operations. Mentored new employees and managers in curriculum and best practices.

Key Accomplishments:

- Grew school from 30 students to over 300 in 4 years.
- Took monthly revenues from \$3,000 to \$45,000.
- Consistently most profitable of 7 schools.
- Mentored over 100 students to their black belts.

Title Boxing Club Personal Trainer

2016 - Current Bedford, Ma

Helped Clients achieve their fitness and wellness goals.

Education

UNH, NH - Full Stack Development Certificate Aug 2020 - March 2021

BSU, MA - BS: Communications 2009 - 2013
Bridgewater State University